# **Alek Smith**

(Full Stack Software Engineer)

alektyler14@hotmail.com • (669) 244-6355 • Tifton, GA, 31793 Linkedin • Github • Stakoverflow • Portfolio

# **Summary**

I am a full stack software engineer with 7 years of experience in building website and mobile applications using different technical stacks. My strongest language is Javascript/Typescript and most experienced with MERN/MEAN stack, LAMP/LEMP stack. I have also a little bit of mobile application development experience using React Native/Expo.

My favorite languages are React.JS, Laravel, Vue.JS, Node.JS and Typescript.

#### **Professionalism**

- Good understanding of project architecture and software development processes
- Ability to understand business requirements and translate them into technical requirements
- Responsibility for implementing features, provide bug fixes, reviewing code quality.
- Strong communication and team collaboration
- Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills, Full-time availability.
- A fast learner keeping up-to-date with lates technologies and a good problem-solver.

### **Technical Skills**

- PHP/Laravel/ Laravel Forge/Envoyer
- Node.js/Express.js/Deno
- Python/Django/Flask
- Serverless
- GraphQL/Apollo/Prisma/Hasura
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Bootstrap/jQuery/Alpin.js
- React.JS/Next/Gatsby
- Vue.JS/Nuxt.JS
- Angular.JS
- Tailwind CSS
- Material UI/Styled Component

- SASS/SCSS/LESS/Webpack
- Socket.io/Web Socket
- MySQL/PostgreSQL/MongoDB/Redis
- Git/GitHub Action
- Docker/ Kubernetes
- Jest /Cypress/React Testing Library
- Ethereum/Solidity/Hardhat/ Subgraph
- Web3.JS/Ethers.JS
- AWS/GCP/Digital Ocean
- Android (Java)/ iOS (Swift)
- React Native/Expo, Ionic
- API Development/Integration

- Load Balancing, Scalable System Architecture
- Self Hosted Email server Development.
- Test Driven Development & Domain Driven Design
- Linux/Apache(Nginx, Caddy Server

## Third party service Integration

- Paypal Payment Gateway Integration
- Stripe Payment Gateway Integration
- Namecheap Domain Registration API
- OAuth for Twitter, Facebook, Linkedin, Github, Instagram
- Twillio API integration for SMS, Real Time Chat, Notification, Video Call.
- Google Analytics/Crashlytics API Integration

- Firebase Authentication Integration
- Push Notification (One Signal, FCM, Expo Notification)
- Caddy Server API Integration
- Printful API integration
- Audible Magic Service for Verifying Copyright ownership

## **Work Experiences**

## Full stack Developer at Hitpiece

Nov 2021 - Aug 2022

Main Stack: Next.js, Express.js, Serverless, Hasura, AWS

- Developed a NFT market place website using Next.js based on Typescript and Tailwind CSS library.
- Utilized GraphQL with Apollo client & Hasura GraphQL console.
- Customized Hasura Backend Plus for authentication backend API using Express.js.
- Developed Serverless APIs for Hasura actions, Third party API web hooks and Jobs.
- Built some microservice-style backend applications for Image resize & upload to S3, Audible Magic API service.
- Configured Load balancer, API gateway, Cloudfront distribution.
- Built stripe webhooks for Stripe checkout and Payouts.
- Wallet Authentication, Crypto checkout and Deploying NFTs to Ethereum main network using Web3.js/Ether.js.
- Utilized Docker and Containerized architecture for DevOps
- Write Unit Tests using Jest and E2E tests using Cypress.
- Set up CI/CD pipelines for a generic cloud-based web application using GitHub action.

#### Software Engineer at Havvi

Feb 2021 - Nov 2021

Main Stack: React.js, Expo, Firebase, Node.js, GCP

- Built Mobile Application using Expo
- Designed database based on the project purpose on Firebase (Cloud Firestore)
- Built Backed APIs and Firestore Event Handlers in Node.JS on Firebase function.
- Built Mobile application Firebase Authentication (Anonymous, Email & Password, Apple, Google, Linking Anonymous with Real credential)
- Implemented Universal Link to share contents between customers, Scheduling, Push Notification using Expo notification.
- Built a Landing page of company website using React.JS and deploy it on Google Cloud App Engine.
- Built admin panel for only fitness creators using React.JS, Firebase Function, Node.JS and deploy it to Google Cloud App Engine.
- Built Machine Learning Algorithm to categorize the fitness workouts.

#### Full Stack Developer at ApolloFactor

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021

Main Stack: Ionic/Angular.JS, Deno, MongoDB, Digital Ocean

- Built frontend website using lonic/Angular.
- Built Backend API using Deno & MongoDB.
- Utilized micro-service architecture for generating PDF, Compensation Prediction using Python.
- Fixed production issues and improved security and performance.
- · Mostly focused on updating Admin panel functionality.

# Full Stack Developer at CloudPin

Aug 2018 - Nov 2019

Main Stack: Expo, Gatsby.JS, Cloud Firestore, Firebase function, Node.JS, GCP

- Built Website using Gatsby.js and Styled component.
- Built Mobile Application using Expo
- Serverless APIs, Webhooks, Jobs, Firestore action triggers using Firebase Function with Node.js
- Stripe payment gateway Integration for Premium users.
- Implemented Push Notification using Expo notification and Social sharing.

# Education

BS, Software Engineering
Georgia State University, GA, USA

GPA: 3.08/4.00

May 2016